welcome back
and today we are going to see the HV age
now, this is another age filled with quality of life things, unlike MV actually
（向上合并）
and the first thing we notice is that
as soon as we reach HV, we unlock many many new trades in our vending machine
now, my suggestion here is to start buying and keep buying as much industrial TNT as you can
this one, industrial TNT
you're going to need a bunch of these later
you should probably automate it passively
but you can totally get all you need just by keeping on buying it
then, there are probably another few things you may want
but for the moment this is the main thing you should be buying in my opinion
and the other thing is that I have been saving up a bunch of loot bags
now, those loot bags were not even that interesting, but
you can craft those into the next tier
and the HV loot bag is actually quite interesting
I mean, it's not the greatest thing ever (either?)
but you can drop some things that are quite annoying to craft otherwise
so I converted all of the loot bags into HV
and then I opened those
and this is what we got
which is probably worse than just picking whatever ingot feels like the most needed at the moment when you can pick a different reward
anyways, back to HV machines
the first highlight is going to be the Universal Macerator
this one works like a normal Macerator
but it can also yield one byproduct
which for example can be super useful to obtain extra gallium
or a huge amount of chromium if you process rubies in a Macerator two times and then you make the ruby juice
（向上合并）
another cool toy is the Advanced Bending Machine HV
which can allow you to make tin cans
those are a totally different way of managing food
since you no longer have to rotate foods
and you can get super easily filled up with any kind of food
but the best thing is the new Advanced Miner
while we could have got mining machines way earlier
the HV one is the first one with a range big enough to collect a whole ore vein
and also it's the first one which has enough luck to be as good as the hammer
now using this one still have a few issues
first of all, you must make sure it does not get hit by rain
and then the other issue is managing its output
because it's going to output a lot of stuff
and you need a really good chest for that
we used to use compressed chests
those were super nice
those compressed chests have a huge inventory
and you can pick up the chest without losing its contents or dropping it
the issue is that in this game version it has been gated behind the nichrome
which means we won't be able to get this until basically the end of this episode
but ideally you want to use this one
and finally the last issue I have with this one is that we have to power it
so, using large steel fluid cells with a combustion generator is a really nice way
but the issue is that I don't have a decent enough fuel production to actually do that
and since our base is also struggling with power
it's probably a good idea to look for oil
which we can also use for powering
now, usually people will go with some renewable way of making oil, like with plants
（向上合并）
you can crossbreed a plant that produces oil
you can also do biofuel and other things
but I just like to look for the better field of it (?)
which if we find one
it's quite huge
that we have a normal oil field
basically those are oil fields that are 8x8 chunks big
and you can find a random oil
this chunk for example has oil
and every chunk inside it has different values
this one was raw oil which is a different oil
（向上合并）
under my base I have a huge deposit of heavy oil which is what I want to do
and I also found some light oil
now all of those different oils what it changes is the amount of byproducts they give each one
you look in the distillation tower
heavy oil gives a lot of heavy fuel and basically no naphtha
while raw oil gives no heavy fuel and huge amounts of naphtha for example
each oil has a different output
but if we want to collect the oil under the bedrock
we're going to need a fluid drilling rig
which is a multiblock that will slowly pump the oil out of the bedrock
now, doing such thing will slowly deplete the oil field
but if these are huge field, it will last a long time
more specifically
if you look at NEI
there is a page that tells you the underground oil deposits
and I suggest looking for deposit that is at least 1/4 of the maximum amount
this field I found here is really huge
this is the cheapest drilling rig there is, the steel version
（向上合并）
which only digs a single chunk
but there are bigger versions
I could already have made the stainless steel version that does 4 chunks at a time
the biggest version takes the whole oil field at once
but for the moment that is more than enough
next, we are going to process this oil
and this time we are going to use all of it
we are not going to waste even a little drop
that means that we are going to use the distillation tower to distill all of its components
instead of getting just one from the distillery
and it was then that I realized that we need a higher tier of circuit than what we can usually have
so, time to start looking into how to make a new circuit
and while it looks kind of easy
we actually have a big issue
which is that those circuits must be made inside a cleanroom
so the first thing we're going to have to do is to build a cleanroom
which is an real room where you can go inside and build machines
（重新分句）that will craft with an additional stats that is being inside a cleanroom
that is required for those crafting for advanced circuits
so, this is basically a multiblock, but it's really special
you can build it in many different ways
and there are many tips
first of all, when you build it double check the recipes
because for example the filter
if you craft it in a crafting table, it's going to cost you 3 filters
if you make it in a assembler, it's only 2, which is way cheaper
also, calcite, you don't have to dig a calcite
you can make it in a chemical reactor super easily
then there are all sorts of other tricks
for example, I heavily suggest having a dedicated battery buffer
this is the old battery buffer I use at the beginning
I repurpose it
just to power the cleanroom
when you complete it
it will take a long time before it's actually usable
once you turn it on
it will slowly work
and as you can see that every 11 seconds the efficiency should go up by one
and that efficiency is the success rate of the crafting you do inside it
so we have to wait basically 20 minutes before using it
otherwise, we have a this chance of success and 90% chance of failing basically
（向上合并）
so you don't want this one to power fail and have to wait for it to clean again
it uses almost no power
so just having one battery is enough to make sure it never power fails
then you can use glass
I could have used more than this glass
but I also wanted it to look nice
you can use glass instead of the wall to cheap out
also I made it slightly bigger than the minimum requirement
if you don't want to craft all of those blocks
you can craft less and make it smaller
depends on how you play
I'm living game AFK
so I just left all of this craft AFK
one big tip, I use this glass because it's the easiest to make
but if you do...
if you crafted the unstable ingot to get the healing axe or other things you may have seen in other people's video
you can craft this glass
which you can put in the wall
and then you can walk through this glass
if you use this glass which is super nice
I didn't wanna bother making this
so I didn't use it
but that's a way
another big thing is that you must have a door in the cleanroom I think, unless they removed the requirement
but every time you open the door the efficiency will go down
（向上合并）
so, the best way to go inside and outside if you don't use the glass...
you don't use the ethereal glass
the best way to go out and in is to use traveling anchors in my opinion
maybe there are even better ways which I don't know
but that's a way
next, you can use cable diodes or machines hulls to pass power inside the cleanroom
if you use machine hulls, you can also use conveyor belts and pump to pass fluid inside the machine hulls
because every machine hull
basically, the machine hulls you use to craft any machine, those
as you can see, it already states that it has voltage in voltage out
it's 1 amp, so you...
basically you can use this as a cable
but if you look at Waila
you can also see it is empty over 2,000 liters
this one can hold two buckets of fluid
and you can pump in and out fluids out of this
and you can put this one in the wall of the cleanroom
and it also holds one item
but most likely at this point of the game you will simply go inside
put stuff to processing in a chest
and do it as you usually do
later on when you have a AE2
you can use a wireless connector to get inside
but we are far from that
and with that, we can basically craft IV tier mainframes
which are two tiers above HV
we don't really need this one right now
but we need the workstation for the distillation tower
and we can also do other things
so, after I crafted those circuits which are nothing special
I can finally make the distillation tower we were needing earlier
and thus we are getting 4 different fluids out of oil without wasting anything
the issue is that now we have to refine 4 fluid out of this sulfur
we could use 4 single block chemical reactors
but it's way easier to use a single mega chemical reactor
and this multiblock has many nice things that it can do
but even before we see that
the first thing that should come to our mind is that
since we are inputting so many fluids to do so many recipes
we are going to have to handle five different outputs
and we probably want those to go in different places
（向下合并）
for that purpose, we can have a different output hatch for each fluid
but to make sure that each fluid goes in the correct place
we should also lock all of those output fluids like so
then we are also going to have an electrolyzer to recover the hydrogen out of the sulfide
as we did with the older setup
like that
this one is for the sulfur
and finally here we will get
the light fuel and the heavy fuel
to make diesel to power our things
but before doing that
there are another few things I want to tell you about the large chemical reactor
because this machine is way more powerful than what I have just shown you
and I just realize I never explained how overclocks work in this modpack
and this is a machine with perfect overclock
which is quite special
now, if a receipt, for example, this plastic circuit board which we are going to craft a lot of
has a processing tier of LV
that is a crafting recipe 40 seconds at LV
total 24,000 EU (per tick)
if you use a higher tier machine
you are going to overclock it
that means it's going to use four times the power
but it will take half the time
for a total of twice the energy
and there it goes
and you can do that multiple times
every time you do that
you double the total power consumption to half the time
and you can see it scales nicely
but if you instead use a large chemical reactor
the large chemical reactor has perfect overclock
that means that instead of taking 20 seconds at MV
it will take only 10 seconds at MV
two seconds at HV
and less than half second at EV
and as you can see it's doing 10 at a time because batch mode is enabled
batch mode simply makes the batch bigger
so that it crafts less often to reduce lag
like if the machine keeps crafting every tick
it will make more lag rather than doing bigger batches less often
and since this machine behaves like that
you probably want to give it as much power as you can
and make sure you have one for personal usage
so you can craft whatever you need without worrying too much or messing up any automation
now back to our oil processing
as you can probably notice
we are producing different ratios of those fuels
so everything will stop
like many people probably just enable the void fluid
so if I do that
it's going to keep crafting the fluids I'm missing there
but it's going to void this one
which I do not want
so, if I don't want to void the leftover of the main produce fluid
we have to use every single output of this LCR
and since our objective is getting fuel
the first thing we're going to worry about is using the light fuel and the heavy fuel
I put those two there because you will see how we end up connecting it, so
I'm going to use those two are mixed together
we could also try to use the LCR to that receipt too
but I want to do it this way for reasons, so
heavy fuel will go into this mixer
heavy fuel is what we are going to have a lot of leftover off
but sooner we show how we will deal with that
and the mixer will need cells with fuel
so we will fill up this one with fuel
and we need the double conveyor to move cells back and forth once they fill up
now this one has light fuel
I will explain later why I'm doing it this way
like this
later on I will explain why I do it this way
and that should work
no, I forgot to connect power
OK, power can come from here, this is MV
this is an MV mixer
and the correct circuit is 5
OK, it's working good
and I'm going to store into super tank
we are going to use a lot of super tanks
set up outputs
this side fluid auto outputs
why are you not working
come on
fluid auto-output
oh, because the face is wrong
and then we got the fuel to power the small drilling setups that I will be laying all around the ore veins to collect ores
but that's far from a complete
I'm also going to probably use this fuel to power the base if I ran low on energy
but that's the last thing I would be doing
now, the other thing is that we are going to have here leftover refinery gas and leftover naphtha
which I don't really intend on using
so since I don't plan on using those two gases
I'm simply going to pipe those up
OK, I have to figure out
oh that's going to be ugly
ah, whatever, if it works, it's not
if it works, it's good
and I'm simply going to burn this gas into turbine here
which will charge up my battery buffer
here I used quadruple pipes
I had to use bronze because for whatever reason
potin doesn't have a quadruple (?) pipe
but the reason I wanted a quadruple pipe is because I want to have different gases
and to help distribute the gases
the quadruple pipe will help
like turbine locks to a single gas
I have bad memories of having like 1 liter of gas stuck in turbine
if I had the quadruple pipe, it can better distribute across the multiple turbine I would have
that is for the leftover gases
the final issue is that we have too much heavy fuel
we are producing those four
those two will go into energy
those two directly go into power
this one is basically all converted into diesel
which I'm going to use in various places
but also as backup power if I need to
and now we have a lot of this leftover
this one, we could distill it
that's something you probably want to do but later game
right now we have a better choice
like this is good for TNT's when we will need a lot of TNT's later
this is super useful and this is super useful too
but this is a recipe for later
right now what I want to do is to crack it
and after we crack it
we can distill every good thing out of it
and we get a lot of light fuel
if we do the lightly one, we get a lot of extra light fuel out of it
and we also get a lot of useful stuff
because there are three different cracking levels of this
it changes basically the circuit using your cracker
the first one makes mostly light fuel
second one pushes it a little bit up
third one gets a lot of useful gases
I haven't figured out which one I want to use right now, but
basically, it only changes the depending on what you want
but right now I think I want to focus on light fuel
so I'm probably going to do circuit 1
so by placing the pipe like that
and without restricting flow direction
this mixer should always get a lot of priority on the heavy fuel
while all of the leftover will go into our oil cracker
we should make the lightly cracked heavy fuel
then it will move to the distillation tower
which I still couldn't finish
and we'll get all of these outputs we have seen earlier
light fuel, I'm simply pumping it back
light fuel goes back to the thing I did earlier
and that thing here was supposed to prioritize the output of the LCR
but then I realized it doesn't really matter
this pipe done like that should make sure the LCR fluid is the first one to be used
in this case it was not needed
while every other fluid is a gas
and some of those I want to keep more
(other less or?) are produced in really silly amounts
so I did this setup where every gas should mostly go inside this tank
and all of the leftover is slowly moved to the pipe that burns the leftover gases
this will still leak a little bit of gas to the burning setup
but at least we don't enable void mode
nothing get wasted
and we save a little bit of gas
like, this setup is not meant to produce ethylene
it's not meant to produce any of those gases really
it's mostly to give a purpose to the leftover heavy fuel
but if we can store up a little bit of those gases
it could turn out to be useful later on
and finally after the diesel tank will be filled up
whatever leftover fuel we have we can send it up
where we'll go into those generators
which are toggle on and off with that redstone
which is driven by the energy detector cover on our battery buffer
and I'm going to turn on those whenever the power goes below 50%
you must make sure it says
electricity storage (including batteries)
then you do 50%
done
whenever it's below this limit, so
invert, OK
whenever it's below this limit
it will turn on the generators
and maybe let's it
let's make this one tick slowly
OK, that should make sure we never have power issues
all of the leftover gas will be burnt instantly
it's not going to be too much power
but it's going to be something
and whenever we run low on power
those generators will make a decent amount of power
and when those start burning
it will start seeping fuel
which will turn on the distillery to get the extra gas
that's actually only 1 EV amp
so it's not even that much
but I'm living the game AFK a lot
so it should work really nicely
use all of the free power from solar
and if some EBF or something is draining too much
the generators will turn on
this distillation tower is going to be expensive
but there are other projects I can prepare that do not require much stainless steel
I can do while this one is slowly crafting
but mostly going to be (?) AFK
once again, this setup
I really love making this setup like that
but it's probably not the good speedrun way of doing it
like the best way is probably to breed a magical crop that produces oil
if you have renewable oil from some magic crop or whatever
then you can afford just burning the oil as it is
and just wasting all of the oil you want
but I like more to build this kind of stuff
meanwhile, in our basement
we can make two new large chemical reactors
I don't know why I keep calling those mega
those are large
there is an actual mega chemical reactor which is better
but we can't do that yet
anyways, the first one would be specialized in making all sorts of acids
such as hydrochloric, nitric, also ammonia and a couple other things
you must have at least 8 the chemical inert machine casings
so put to good use all of this space you can
before going into detail
I'm sourcing hydrogen, nitrogen and oxygen for this one
the oxygen, as I was showed in the past episode
is mostly produced while making silicon
but basically whenever you make hydrogen and nitrogen
you also get oxygen as byproduct
so it all goes in there
nitrogen, I'm making it by simply centrifuging compressed air
while hydrogen I'm mostly making it out of limonite
I'm making hydrogen almost solely out of limonite
because I can't leave the game
I'm leaving the game AFK a lot
so it just processes limonite slowly
you can get hydrogen by electrolyzing water
but a cool trick
I was noticing I have a lot of leftover sodium from electrolyzing stuff
also a lot of potassium
you can simply react sodium with water to get huge amounts of hydrogen
like where is it, come on
OK, that recipe
that recipe can make huge amount of hydrogen relatively easier
and then you can electrolyze this to get back the sodium and also extra hydrogen
and if you actually do that, it should be way more efficient than simply electrolyzing water for hydrogen
theoretically, if you have a lot of sodium
you can react this with water to get hydrogen
I'm just showing options
right now I'm fine with hydrogen for the moment
I don't know how long I will be
hydrogen is a huge issue through all of the game
I'm not there yet but it will be
anyways, this one makes a bunch of acids
and the other chemical reactor right next to it
what it does is that it processes something called platinum metallic powder
it processes that platinum metallic powder into refined platinum dust
now, this is something that is relatively complicated
and most likely it's something you will do in like two years from now
it is something that if you do it like that
it takes more time to figure out how you want to pipe things than crafting the machine
so it's something you can do right now if you want
you're going to need huge amounts of platinum
and you're going to rebuild this many times
so if you can start slowly stocking up a little bit of that reprecipitated platinum dust
it will be a really useful way later on
it's required for AE2
so once you get AE2,  you will probably rethink everything
if you get this on early, it's nice
and now why is this not working
it should be working theoretically, hopefully
oh OK, the pipe is slow, but it's fine
now it works
the other thing is that I'm producing ammonia and nitric acid here
you can use nitric acid with a couple of other things to get tetranitromethane
it's not too hard to do
there are a few ways
if you have sulfuric acid
getting acetic acid is super easy with ethylene and oxygen
we have ethylene
I mean we make ethylene for polyethylene
but also ethylene is one of the leftover of the distillation tower from the cracked fuel
you can also go through the acetone way
but thing is that you need just a little bit of this
a little few drops of this to double the power output of diesel
because normal diesel has a fuel value of half million
while cetane-boosted diesel has 1 million of fuel value
so, just adding a little bit of that stuff will double your fuel value
for because of like a crafting chain made out of 4 machines
and piping everything together
I'm lazy
some people void the fuel altogether
I'm going to avoid the possibility of doubling my fuel value
because I'm too lazy to build five machines and pipe everything together
mostly because I'm lazy
I should totally get this fuel
but I'm too lazy to pipe everything in a single place and put 5 machines
anyways, now that we have all of that crafting chain working
and we're getting a lot of stuff
we also have a lot of power available
and with all of that power
we can finally start working on nichrome
nichrome is the next upgrade for the EBF
and that will allow us to get the Vibrant Alloy
which we are going to use for making EnderIO Advanced machines
now those machines will also require us to work a little bit with mobs
so we looked into a better armor
such as the new mechanical armor
this is a modular armor
where you can install in each armor an energy core
no, a frame? OK
then we add an energy core
and finally we can add various modules to obtain different effects
but at the moment it's a little bit disappointing
because we can't really make any of the good modules
the jetpack, we don't have titanium yet
and all of the good stuff of course requires a better core than the Nano one which is the only one I can make
so, I guess we're going to try out this armor in the future, not now
the other thing we can do to obtain more drops from the mobs is a cleaver
that has a base chance of getting heads at least 20%
but we can add first a diamond and a block of gold to increase the modifier by 1
then one diamond block and then enchanting golden apple
to get a second modifier
and the two modifiers we did that for are ender pearl and obsidian to get two more levels of beheading
reaching a 40% chance of dropping mob heads
and as a ranged weapon
we are also getting a crossbow made out of carbon
with the vanadiumsteel tipped carbon bolts
and of course we shall add more modifiers
which are going to use to give some durability to this crossbow
and a little bit of extra speed
and all of the quartz we can (add) to the bolts
that should deal a good amount of damage
it's still slow though
well, 47 attack damage
and with this we are ready to go look for the end portal
which was rather close to our base
and with that, we have the ender pearl required to craft the EnderIO machines
to power those
the trick is that you have to first place the machine
and then you connect the cable
there we go
anyways, the reason we are doing all of that is just so we can craft a powered spawner
which I'm going to use to quickly farm some wither skulls
because I'm too lazy to make a proper mob farm
they says smart people are lazy, I think
but I'm not too sure if every lazy person is also smart
and correlation does not mean causation
anyways, the reason we are farming nether stars is so that we can build a NASA workbench
and this is required to craft our next main objective, a rocket
and while you could totally argue that this is rocket science
it's not that hard
so here's a few tips for you
first tip was at the beginning of this episode
keep buying industrial TNTs
because you're going to need a lot of explosives there
so if you if you keep buying TNT from the beginning of HV
you should have enough to complete the rocket
also be careful with the industrial TNT
because as far as I remember
if you place this one
if you place one
every attempt of removing it will blow it up
then having a dedicated bending machine for an implosion compressor could be a good idea
and always try to batch craft when you have to craft so many items
like few episodes ago, I said that with NEI it's way easier to use the auto crafting
so you don't waste resources
but when you have to deal with machines
you kind of have to batch craft
like don't craft every time a single circuit
craft one stack of circuits, two times in the whole playthrough
then in space, you are going to need some oxygen
and those oxygen tanks are rather disappointing
so if you are not using teleportation commands
I heavily suggest
making sure you can charge up those in space
as always, read the quest book
because it explains everything pretty well
but in my opinion, it's just so easy to have some liquid oxygen put it in a canister
place your compressor
give it one of your old batteries
put the canister inside
and then you just fill your oxygen tanks like that
and after a lot of crafting
we finally obtain our rocket
to launch it, we are going to have to fuel it up
so we use a fuel loader
which once again we can power just with batteries
and we are going to need some fuel
the fuel for this rocket is cetane-boosted diesel
the fuel I was too lazy to make a five machine crafting chain for
and since I'm so lazy, instead of even manually crafting it
what I'm going to do is
craft an MV World Accelerators
because this one, we complete a quest that as a reward will give us enough fuel to go whatever we want with our rocket
so once again, we place the rocket on the loading site thing (?)
and then we move the fuel in
using a large cell will be way better than using those small cells, but whatever
by the way, if you don't disable pollution
you should launch your rocket from a little bit far from your base
because it's going to produce a lot of pollution when you launch it
and another super important thing before launching is always do a backup
you do not want to mess this up
many things can go wrong
most likely you will forget something
so make sure you do a backup before launching the rocket
and once everything is ready
we can launch to the moon
it will take a little bit to reach the orbit
the tier 1 rocket
this one is also rather slow
higher tier rockets would be a little bit faster at reaching the moon
you can also tilt it and go sideways
it's a (luxury?) way of traveling through the world, but
maybe there are better ways
I mean you can tilt it like that and go wherever you want
but ideally you should simply go up
and after enough time
you should reach this screen there
at this point, you have to be a little bit careful, but not too much
you click once on the overworld
second time it will zoom in
then you select the moon and you do launch
and if everything is fine
you should be there without taking damage
now, you should hold space to slow down
but if you look below the map
you can see the (epsilon?)
my suggestion is start slowing down at 300
yes, maybe a little bit
maybe it's like four or 5 hundreds, but OK
you can just slow down
I don't like all of the time it takes to land, but OK
so OK, we are on the moon now
what we are looking for here is titanium and neodymium mostly
galena, oh bauxite
OK that is what we are looking for
and of course, at this point of the game
we are going to use an automated miner with a compressed chest
which we can pick up later with all of the contents inside it
and what we want to recover out of all of those ores is as much rutile as we can
with that and some carbon we can produce titaniumtetrachloride
I didn't mention the chlorine because that is going to be looping inside the system
and this is yet again one more automation
now a few things I probably want to show that I haven't shown yet in automation systems is that
you can for example lock output buses
you can for example split the solids two
I mean I showed that with liquid but so it's different
and also a few tricks with conduits
conduits are super versatile
if you already know how those works it's really nice
otherwise specifically in a closed loop like that
where I know I have a fixed amount of items
I can save a filter by having a higher priority filter
and the leftover which is only a different item and with limited amount goes into the lower priority thing there
also you can drag filtering items from NEI
but I think that's probably nothing special
just wanted to show that too
and with that, we finally obtain titanium
and reach the point of the game where I call tutorial complete
and I say we just finished the tutorial
because this is the point where the game gets a little bit faster and more
this is the point where GTNH becomes GTNH
and nowadays every GregTech modpack is more or less similar
but used to be a bigger deal in my opinion
so, see you next time for AE2 and EV
they almost forgot to say bye bye
欢迎回来
今天我们将看到 HV 时代
这是另一个充满妙妙工具的时代，不像 MV
（向上合并）
我们首先注意到的
一旦我们达到 HV，自动售货机解锁许多新的交易
我的建议是开始并持续购买尽可能多的工业 TNT
这个，工业 TNT
之后你会需要一堆这个的
你应该需要建一条它的被动产线
但是你只要持续购买就可以获得你需要的数量
然后，还有其他一些东西你可能想要
但在我看来，这是你目前最该买的东西
另一件事是我积攒了一堆战利品袋
那些战利品袋没那么有趣，但是
你可以把这些合成为下一阶段的战利品袋
HV 战利品袋实际上很有趣
我是说，这也不是最棒的东西
但是你可以开出一些制作起来很烦人的东西
所以我把所有的战利品袋都换成了 HV 战利品袋
然后打开
这就是我们的收获
这可能比在你可以选择不同任务奖励的时候挑选当时感觉最需要的锭更糟糕
不管怎样，回到 HV 机器
第一个亮点是通用研磨机
这个像普通的研磨机一样工作
但它也可以产出副产品
例如，这对于获得额外的镓非常有用
或者大量的铬，通过研磨机处理红宝石两次，然后制作红宝石汁
（向上合并）
另一个很酷的玩具是高级卷板机
可以让你制作锡罐
这是一种完全不同的食物管理方式
因为你不再需要轮换食物
你可以非常容易地用任何食物填饱肚子
但最好的是新的高级矿机
虽然我们本可以更早做出矿机
HV 矿机是第一个有足够大挖掘范围能收集整个矿脉的矿机
这也是第一个有和锤子一样好时运的
现在使用这个仍然有一些问题
首先你必须确保它不会淋雨
然后另一个问题是管理它的输出
因为它会输出很多东西
你需要一个特别好的箱子
我们以前用压缩箱子
它超级好用
那些压缩箱子有大量的存储空间
你可以捡起箱子而不把内容物爆一地
问题是在这个游戏版本中，它的前置是镍铬合金
这意味着我们基本上要到这一集结束才能做出它
但理想情况下你想用这个
最后，这矿机的最后一个问题是供电
所以，使用大型钢流体单元和内燃发电机是一个非常好的方法
但问题是我没有足够的燃油产量来真正做到这一点
由于我们的基地也在为发电挣扎
石油可能是个好主意
我们也可以用它来供电
通常人们会用一些可再生的方法来制造石油，比如用植物
（向上合并）
你可以杂交一种产油的植物
你也可以做生物燃油和其他的东西
但我只是想寻找更好的油田
如果我们找到一个
它相当巨大
我们有一个常规油田
基本上那些是 8x8 个区块大的油田
你可以找到一种随机的油
例如，这块有石油
里面的每一区块都有不同的值
这个是原油，不用于石油
（向上合并）
在我的基地下面有大量的重油储量，这正是我想处理的
我还发现了一些轻油
所有这些不同的油，它改变的是它们产生的副产品的数量
看看蒸馏塔配方
重油提供大量重燃油，基本上没有石脑油
而原油没有重燃油，例如大量石脑油
每种油都有不同的产量
但如果我们想收集基岩下的石油
我们需要一个流体钻机
这是一个多方块，可以慢慢地将石油从基岩中抽出
这样做会慢慢耗尽油田
但如果这些是巨大的油田，它将持续很长时间
更具体地说
如果你看看 NEI
有一页告诉你地下油田储量
我建议寻找至少是最大储量的 1/4 的油田
我发现的这块油田真的很大
这是最便宜的钻机，用钢做的
（向上合并）
它只挖掘单个区块
但还有更大的版本
我本可以做一次挖四个区块的不锈钢制版本
最大的版本一次挖一整个油田
但就目前而言，这已经足够了
接下来，我们要处理这些油
这次我们将使用利用这些
不会浪费哪怕一滴
这意味着我们要用蒸馏塔来蒸馏它所有的成分
而不是只从蒸馏器得到一个
就在那时，我意识到我们需要一个比通常更高等级的电路板
所以，是时候开始研究如何制作一个新电路板了
虽然看起来很容易
我们实际上有一个大问题
那些电路必须在超净间里制造
所以我们要做的第一件事就是建造一个超净间
这是一个真正的房间，你可以走进去放机器
这些机器需要满足在超净间内的条件才能进行合成
这对于那些制造高级电路板来说是必需的
所以，这基本上是一个多方块，但它真的很特别
你可以通过许多不同的方式构建它
而且有很多提示
首先，当你构建它时，请仔细检查配方
因为，举个例子，过滤器
如果你在工作台中制作它，它要三个过滤器
如果你在组装机里做，只要两个，便宜多了
还有，方解石，你不必挖方解石
你可以在化学反应釜中非常容易地制造它
还有很多其他的小技巧
例如，我强烈建议做一个专用的电池箱
这是我一开始用的旧电池箱
我重新利用它
只是为了给超净间供电
当你完成它时
它需要很长时间才能真正可用
一旦你打开它
它会慢慢工作的
正如你所看到的，每 11 秒效率应该提高 1%
效率就是你在里面制作配方的成功率
所以我们必须等 20 分钟才能使用它
否则我们只有 10% 的成功率和 90% 的失败率
（向上合并）
所以你不希望它跳电然后等它重新净化
它几乎不用电
所以只要有一块电池就足以确保它永远不会断电
那你可以用玻璃
我本可以用更多的这种玻璃
但我也希望它看起来不错
你可以用玻璃代替墙壁来省成本
另外，我把它做得比最低要求稍微大一点
如果你不想制作所有这些方块
你可以少做一点，把它做得更小
就看你怎么玩了
我大部分时间挂机
所以我就把所有这些都挂机合成了
一个重要的提示，我用这种玻璃是因为它最容易制作
但如果你做了……
如果你制作了用来做治愈之斧的不稳定锭，或者在其他人的视频里看到了怎么做不稳定锭
你可以制作这个玻璃
你可以把它放在墙上
然后你可以穿过这个玻璃
如果你用这种超级好用的玻璃
我不想费心做这个
所以我没有使用它
但那是一种方式
另一个重要的事情是，你的超净间应该必须要有一个门，除非他们取消了这个要求
但每次你打开门，净化效率会下降
（向上合并）
所以，如果你不使用玻璃，最好的进出方式……
如果你不用天域玻璃
在我看来，出入超净间的最好方法是使用旅行锚
也许还有我不知道的更好的进出方式
但那是一种方法
接下来，你可以使用电缆二极管或机器外壳在超净间内传递电力
如果你使用机器外壳，你还可以使用传送带和泵在机器外壳内传递流体
因为每个机器外壳
基本上，你用来制造任何机器的机器外壳，那些
如你所见，它已经说了它具有电压输入和电压输出
是一安培，所以你……
你基本上可以用这个作为线缆
但如果你看看 Waila
你也可以看到它是空的，容量 2000 升
这个可以装两桶流体
你可以用泵输入输出流体
你可以把这个放在超净间的墙上
它还可以存一个物品
但最有可能的情况是，在这个游戏阶段，你会简单地走进去
把东西放在箱子里处理
并像往常一样去做事
稍后当你有 AE 时
你可以用无线连接器进去
但我们还远远没有做到这一点
有了它，我们基本上可以制作 IV 等级主机
比 HV 高两级
我们现在还不需要这个
但我们需要工作站来做蒸馏塔
我们还可以做其他事情
所以，在制作了那些没什么特别的电路之后
我终于可以把之前需要的蒸馏塔做好了
至此，我们从石油中获得了四种不同的流体，而不会浪费任何东西
问题是现在我们得把这四种流体都脱硫
我们可以用四个单方块化学反应釜
但是使用一个大型化学反应釜要容易得多
这个多方块有很多好功能
但是在我们看到那些之前
我们首先应该想到的是
因为我们输入了这么多液体来做这么多配方
我们将不得不处理五个不同的输出
我们希望它们输出到不同的地方
（向下合并）
为此，我们可以为每种流体提供不同的输出仓
但要确保每种流体都进入正确的位置
我们还应该像这样锁定所有输出流体
然后我们做一个电解机来从硫化物中回收氢
就像我们对旧设置所做的那样
像那样
这个是硫的
最后我们会得到
轻燃油和重燃油
来制造柴油来驱动我们的东西
但在那之前
关于大型化学反应釜我还有几件事想告诉你
因为这台机器比我刚刚向你展示的要强大得多
我刚刚意识到我从未解释过这个整合包中超频的工作原理
这是一台具有完美超频的机器
这很特别
如果一个配方，例如，我们要制作大量的塑料电路板
是 LV 的处理电压
这是 LV 40 秒的制作配方
总计 24,000 EU/t
如果你用更高等级的机器
你要超频了
这意味着它将使用四倍的电力
但只要花一半的时间
总耗电量是原来的两倍
就这样
你可以多次超频
每次你这么做
你将总耗电量翻倍，时间变为一半
你可以看到它的变化趋势
但如果你用大型化学反应釜
大型化学反应釜具有完美超频
这意味 MV 电压不用花 20 秒
MV 电压只需要十秒
HV 下两秒
在 EV 下不到半秒
如你所见，它一次执行十个配方，因为启用了批处理模式
批处理模式只是使每批处理的量更大
这样它就可以减少合成频率以减少卡顿
如果机器每个游戏刻都在进行合成
它会产生更多的延迟，而不是更少地进行更大的批次
由于这台机器的行为是这样的
你可能想给它尽可能多的电力
并确保你有一台供个人使用的机器
以便制作任何需要的东西，而不用过度担心或搞砸任何自动化
现在回到我们的石油加工
正如你可能注意到的那样
我们生产不同比例的燃油
所以一切都会停止
像许多人一样，可能只是启用销毁流体
所以如果我这么做
它会继续制造我缺失的液体
但它会让这个被销毁
我不想这样
如果我不想销毁剩余的主要产出的流体
我们必须使用这个大化反的每一个输出
既然我们的目标是获取柴油
我们首先要担心的是使用轻燃油和重燃油
我把这两个放在那里是因为你会看到我们最终是如何连接它的，所以
我要用那两个混合在一起的
我们也可以尝试将LCR用于该配方
但我想这样做是有原因的，所以
重燃油将进入这个搅拌机
重燃油是我们将有很多剩余燃油
但我们会尽快展示我们将如何处理它
搅拌机需要燃油单元
所以我们要把这个装满燃油
一旦单元装满，我们需要双传送带来回移动这些单元
现在这个有轻燃油了
我稍后会解释我为什么这样做。
像这样
稍后我会解释我为什么这样做
这应该行得通。
不，我忘记连接电源了。
好，电力可以从这里来，这是MV
这是一个MV混音器
正确的电路是5
好的，工作正常。
我要储存在超级缸里。
我们要用很多超级缸
设置输出
此侧流体自动输出
你为什么不工作？
来吧
流体自动输出
哦，因为输出面不对
然后我们得到了燃油来驱动小型钻井装置，我将在矿脉周围铺设这些装置来收集矿石。
但这远非一个完整的
如果能量不足，我也可能会用这种燃油为基地提供动力
但这是我最不愿做的事
现在，另一件事是我们这里将有剩余的炼油厂气和剩余的石脑油
我真的不打算用它
既然我不打算用这两种气体
我只是简单的把它们连接起来
好吧，我得弄清楚
哦，那会很难看的。
不管怎样如果有用就不是了
如果有效，那就很好
我要把这些气体烧进涡轮
这将为我的电池箱充电
这里我用了四重管
我不得不用青铜因为不管什么原因
potin没有四（？）管
但是我想要四管的原因是因为我想有不同的气体。
并帮助分配气体
四联管会有所帮助
就像涡轮会被单一气体堵住
我对涡轮机里卡住1升汽油有不好的记忆
如果我有四重管道，它可以更好地分布在多个涡轮机上，我会有
那是用来处理剩余气体的
最后的问题是我们有太多的重油
我们正在生产那四个
这两个将直接用于发电
那两种直接用于发电
这个基本上都是转化成柴油的
我将在不同的地方使用它
如果需要也可以作为备用电源
现在我们有很多剩余的
这个我们可以提炼
这是你可能想做的事情，但是游戏后期
现在我们有更好的选择
就像这对做TNT有好处，我们以后会需要很多TNT。
这是超级有用的，这也是超级有用的
但这是以后的配方
现在我想做的就是裂化它
在我们裂化它之后
我们可以从中蒸馏出所有好东西
我们得到了很多轻燃油
如果我们做轻度裂化的，我们可以得到很多额外的轻燃油。
我们也得到了很多有用的东西。
因为这个有三种不同的裂化等级
它基本上改变了电路使用你的裂化机
第一个主要生产轻燃油
第二个把它推上去一点
第三个得到很多有用的气体
我还没想好要用哪一个但是
基本上，它只根据你想要什么来改变
但现在我想把重点放在轻燃油上
所以我可能要做电路1
所以通过这样放置管道
并且不限制流动方向
这个搅拌机应该总是优先考虑重燃油
而所有剩下的都将进入我们的裂化机
我们应该制造轻度裂化的重燃油
然后它会移动到蒸馏塔
我仍然无法完成
我们将得到我们之前看到的所有这些输出
轻燃油，我只是把它抽回去
轻燃油回到我之前做的事情
这里的那个东西应该优先考虑LCR的输出
但后来我意识到这并不重要
这样做的管道应该确保LCR的流体是第一个被使用的
在这种情况下，它不需要
而其他流体都是气体
其中一些我想保留更多
（其他更少或？）以非常愚蠢的数量生产
所以我做了这个设置，每个气体都应该进入这个罐子。
所有的剩余气体被缓慢地转移到燃烧剩余气体的管道中
这仍然会向燃烧装置泄漏一点气体
但至少我们不启用销毁模式
没有什么是浪费的
我们节省了一点汽油
这个装置不是用来生产乙烯的
它实际上并不会产生任何气体
主要是为了给剩余的重燃油一个用途
但是如果我们能储存一点这些气体
它以后可能会有用。
最后柴油缸加满后
不管剩下的燃油是什么，我们都可以把它送上去。
我们将进入那些发电机
哪些与红石打开和关闭
它由我们电池箱上的能量检测器盖驱动
当功率低于50%时，我会打开它们。
你必须确保上面写着
蓄电（包括电池）
那你做50%
完成
只要低于这个限制，所以
反转， OK
只要低于这个限制
它会打开发电机
也许就这样吧
让我们让这个慢慢滴答作响
好的，那应该能保证我们没有电力问题
所有剩余的气体都会立即被烧掉
不会有太大的力量
但这将是一件大事
每当我们电量不足时
这些发电机将产生相当数量的电力
当它们开始燃烧时
它会开始渗出燃油
这将打开酿酒厂以获得额外的气体
那实际上只有1 EV 安培
所以也不算太多
但我一直在玩挂机游戏
所以它应该工作得很好。
使用太阳能的所有免费电力
如果一些EBF或其他东西排水过多
发电机就会启动
这个蒸馏塔会很贵的
但我可以准备其他不需要太多不锈钢的项目
我可以在这个慢慢制作的时候做
但主要是挂机
呃，再一次，这个设置
我真的很喜欢这样做这个设置
但这可能不是最好的快跑方式
就像最好的方法可能是培育一种产油的神奇作物
如果你有某种神奇作物或其他东西的可再生油
那么你就可以负担得起燃烧石油的费用
浪费你想要的所有石油
但我更喜欢建造这种东西
同时在我们的地下室
我们可以制造两个新的大型化学反应釜
我不知道为什么我一直打电话给那些巨型
那些很大。
有一个真正的巨型化学反应釜哪个更好
但我们还不能那么做
不管怎样，第一个是专门制造各种酸的
比如盐酸、硝酸、氨和其他一些东西
你必须至少有8个化学惰性机器外壳
所以好好利用所有这些空间，你可以
在详细讨论之前
我正在为它寻找氢气氮气和氧气
氧气，就像我在上一集里看到的那样
主要是在制造硅时生产的
但基本上当你制造氢气和氮气时
你还会得到氧气作为副产品
所以一切都在那里
氮气，我只是把压缩空气离心
虽然氢我主要是用褐铁矿做的
我几乎完全用褐铁矿制造氢气
因为我不能离开比赛
我经常挂机
所以它只是缓慢处理褐铁矿
你可以通过电解水得到氢气
但是一个很酷的把戏
我注意到我有很多电解剩下的钠
还有很多钾
你可以简单地把钠和水反应得到大量的氢
比如它在哪里，来吧
好的，那个配方
这个配方可以使大量的氢气相对容易
然后你可以电解它以获得钠和额外的氢
如果你真的这样做了，它应该比简单地电解水制氢更有效。
理论上说如果你有很多钠
你可以和水反应得到氢气
我只是在展示选择
现在我对氢气没意见
我不知道我要多久
氢是整个游戏中的一个大问题
我还没到那里，但会到的。
不管怎样，这个制造了一堆酸
和旁边的另一个化学反应釜
它所做的是处理一种叫做铂金属粉末的东西
它将铂金属粉末加工成精制的铂粉
现在，这是相对复杂的事情。
最有可能的是两年后你会做的事情
如果你这样做的话
弄清楚你想如何输送东西比制作机器需要更多的时间。
所以如果你愿意你现在就可以做
你需要大量的白金
你要重建这个很多次
所以如果你能开始慢慢储备一点沉淀的铂金粉
这将是一个非常有用的方法以后
AE2需要它
所以一旦你得到AE2，你可能会重新考虑一切
如果你早点穿上这个，那很好
现在为什么这不起作用？
它应该在理论上有效，希望如此
哦，好吧，管道很慢，但没关系。
现在它起作用了
另一件事是我在这里产生氨和硝酸
你可以用硝酸和其他一些东西来得到四硝基甲烷
这并不难做到
有几种方法
如果你有硫酸
用乙烯和氧气很容易得到醋酸
我们有乙烯
我是说我们为聚乙烯制造乙烯
但乙烯也是蒸馏塔从裂化燃油中剩下的燃油之一
你也可以通过丙酮的方式
但问题是你只需要一点点这个
几滴这个可以使柴油的功率输出翻倍
因为普通柴油有50万的燃油值
高十六烷值柴油100万燃油值
所以，只要加一点这种东西，你的燃油值就会翻倍。
因为就像一个由4台机器制成的工艺链一样
并将所有东西连接在一起
我很懒
有些人完全没有燃油
我要避免燃油值翻倍的可能性
因为我懒得造五台机器把所有东西都装在一起
主要是因为我懒
我完全应该得到这种燃油
但是我懒得把所有东西都装在一个地方，放5台机器。
不管怎样，现在我们有了所有的工艺链
我们拿到了很多东西。
我们也有很多电力可用
有了所有的力量
我们终于可以开始研究镍铬合金了
镍铬合金是EBF的下一个升级
这样我们就能得到脉冲合金
我们将使用它来制造EnderIO Advanced机器
现在这些机器还需要我们和生物一起工作。
所以我们寻找更好的盔甲
比如新的机械装甲
这是模块化装甲
在那里你可以在每件装甲中安装一个能量核心
不，一个框架？好的
然后我们添加一个能量核心
最后我们可以添加各种模块来获得不同的效果
但目前有点令人失望
因为我们真的做不出任何好的模块。
喷气背包我们还没有钛合金
当然，所有的好东西都需要一个比纳米更好的核心，这是我唯一能做的。
所以，我想我们将来会尝试这种盔甲，而不是现在
我们能做的另一件事是从暴徒那里获得更多的水滴
有至少20%的基本机会得到人头
但是我们可以先添加一颗钻石和一块黄金来将修饰符增加1
然后是一个钻石块，然后是附魔金苹果
获得第二个修饰符
我们做的两个修饰符是末影珍珠和黑曜石，以获得另外两个级别的斩首
有40%的几率甩掉暴徒的头
作为远程武器
我们也得到了碳做的弩
用钒钢箭头的碳弩箭
当然，我们将添加更多修饰符
用来给弩加一些耐久
还有一点额外的速度
以及我们可以（添加）到弩箭中的所有石英
这应该会造成不错的伤害
虽然还是很慢
47点攻击力
有了这个，我们准备去寻找末地传送门
离我们的基地很近
有了这个，我们就有了制作EnderIO机器所需的末影珍珠
为那些供电
诀窍是你必须首先放置机器
然后你连接线缆
我们走吧。
不管怎样，我们做这一切的原因只是为了制造一个电动刷怪笼
我要用它来快速刷一些凋零骷髅头
因为我懒得建一个真正的刷怪塔
我想他们说聪明人都很懒
但我不太确定是否每个懒惰的人都很聪明
相关性并不意味着因果关系
不管怎样，我们刷下界之星的原因是为了建造一个NASA工作台
这是我们下一个主要目标火箭所必需的
虽然你完全可以说这是火箭科学
没那么难
所以这里有一些建议给你
第一个提示是在这一集的开头
继续购买工业TNT
因为你需要很多炸药
所以如果你从HV开始就一直买梯恩梯
你应该有足够的钱来完成火箭
还要小心工业TNT
因为据我所知
如果你把这个放在
如果你下一个
每次移除它的尝试都会炸毁它
那么为内爆压缩机配备专用卷板机可能是个好主意
当你必须制作这么多物品时，总是试着批量制作。
就像几集前一样，我说过有了NEI，使用自动制作要容易得多。
这样你就不会浪费资源
但是当你必须和机器打交道的时候
你得批量制作
就像不要每次都制作一个电路一样
制作一叠电路，在整个游戏中制作两次
在太空中你需要一些氧气
那些氧气罐相当令人失望
所以如果你不使用传送命令
我强烈建议
确保你可以在太空中给它们充电
一如既往，阅读任务书
因为它解释得相当清楚一切
但在我看来，把液氧放进罐子里太容易了。
放一个压缩机
给它一个你的旧电池
把罐子放进去
然后你就像那样装满氧气罐
经过大量的制作
我们终于得到了我们的火箭
要发射它，我们必须给它加油
所以我们使用燃油装载机
我们又一次可以只用电池供电。
我们需要一些燃油
火箭的燃油是高十六烷值柴油
我懒得做五机工艺链的燃油
因为我太懒了，甚至没有手动制作它
我要做的是
制作一个MV世界加速器
因为这个，我们完成了一个任务，作为奖励，它将给我们足够的燃油，让我们的火箭随心所欲。
所以再一次，我们把火箭放在装载点（？）
然后我们把燃油运进去
使用大型单元会比使用那些小型单元好得多，但不管怎样
顺便说一句，如果你不消除污染
你应该从离基地稍远的地方发射火箭
因为当你启动它时它会产生很多污染
发射前的另一件超级重要的事情是始终做备份
你不会想搞砸的
很多事情都可能出错
很可能你会忘记什么
所以发射火箭前一定要做备份
一旦一切准备就绪
我们可以发射到月球
需要一点时间才能到达轨道
1层火箭
这个也相当慢
较高层的火箭到达月球会快一点
你也可以倾斜它，侧向走。
这是一种（奢侈？）环游世界的方式，但是
也许有更好的出行方式
我是说你可以像那样倾斜它去任何你想去的地方
但理想情况下，你应该简单地上去
经过足够的时间
你应该到达那里的这个屏幕
在这一点上，你必须小心一点，但不要太多
你点击一次世界
第二次放大
然后你选择月亮并发射
如果一切都好
你应该在那里而不会受到伤害
现在，你应该按住空格键来减速
但是如果你看地图下面
你可以看到（高度指示器？）
我的建议是从300开始减速
是的，也许有一点
也许是四五百，但没关系。
你可以慢下来
我不喜欢降落的时间，不过还好
所以我们现在在月球上
我们要找的主要是钛和钕
方铅矿，哦铝土矿
好的那就是我们要找的
当然，在比赛的这一点上
我们要使用压缩箱子和自动采矿机
我们稍后可以把里面所有的东西都捡起来。
我们想从所有这些矿石中回收尽可能多的金红石
加上一些碳，我们可以生产四氯化钛
我没有提到氯，因为它会在系统中循环。
这又是一个自动化。
现在我可能想展示一些我还没有在自动化系统中展示的东西是
例如，你可以锁定输出总线
例如，你可以把固体也分成两路
我的意思是，我用液体展示了这一点，但这是不同的。
还有一些关于管道的技巧
导管超级通用
如果你已经知道这些是如何工作的，那就太好了。
否则特别是在这样的闭环中
我知道我有固定数量的物品。
我可以通过拥有更高优先级的过滤器来省一个过滤器
剩下的只是一个不同的项目，数量有限，进入那里的优先级较低的东西。
你还可以从NEI拖动过滤项目
但我想那可能没什么特别的
也只是想展示一下
有了这个我们终于得到了钛
并达到游戏的地步，我称之为教程结束
我说我们刚刚完成教程
因为这是游戏变得越来越快的一点
这就是GTNH真正变成GTNH的时刻
现在每个GregTech modpack或多或少都相似
但在我看来，以前是一笔更大的交易。
那么，下次AE2和EV再见
我差点忘了说拜拜